So far, we've been trying to frame the idea of a humanoid
到目前为止 我们一直都尝试运用强化学习
learning to walk in the context of reinforcement learning.
解决机器人学习如何行走这一问题
We've detailed the states in actions,
我们讲解了状态和动作
and we still need to specify the rewards.
但是依然需要指定奖励
And the reward structure from the DeepMind paper is surprisingly intuitive.
DeepMind 团队发表的论文中给出的奖励公式非常直观
This line is pulled from the appendix of the DeepMind paper,
这行公式摘自 DeepMind 团队论文的附录
and describes how the reward is decided at every time step?
描述了每个时间步的奖励计算方法
Each term communicates to the agent some part of what we'd like it to accomplish.
每项都向智能体表示我们希望它能实现的某个部分目标
So let's look at each term individually.
我们来看看每一项
To begin, at every time step,
首先 在每个时间步
the agent receives a reward proportional to its forward velocity.
智能体收到一个与其前进速度成正比的奖励
So if moves faster,
如果走得很快
it gets more reward, but up to a limit.
就会获得更多的奖励 但是有个上限
Here denoted Vmax, but it's penalized by
表示为 Vmax
an amount proportional to the force applied to each joint.
但是它会受到惩罚 惩罚的量与应用到每个接合点的力成正比
So if the agent applies more force to the joints,
如果智能体向接合点应用了更多的力
then more reward is taken away as punishment.
就会拿走更多的奖励以进行惩罚
Since the researchers also wanted the humanoid to focus on moving forward,
研究人员还希望机器人向前行走
the agent is also penalized for moving left, right, or vertically.
如果智能体向左 向右或垂直移动 也会受到惩罚
It was also penalized if the humanoid moved its body away from the center of the track.
如果智能体的身体离开道路中心 也会受到惩罚
So the agent will try to keep the humanoid as close to the center as possible.
智能体需要使机器人尽量接近中心
At every time step,
在每个时间步
the agent also receives some positive reward if the humanoid has not yet fallen.
如果机器人还没有摔倒 智能体还会受到一些正面奖励
They frame the problem as an episodic task where if the human falls,
他们将该问题视作阶段性任务 如果机器人摔倒了
then the episode is terminated.
该阶段结束
At this point, whatever cumulative reward the agent
此刻 智能体在该时间点能够获得的累积奖励
had at that time point is all it's ever going to get.
将是它能够获得的所有奖励
In this way, the reward signal is designed,
这样就设计了奖励信号
so if the robot focused entirely on maximizing this reward,
如果机器人完全侧重于最大化这一奖励
it would also coincidentally learn to walk.
它还会碰巧学会行走
To see this, first note that if the robot falls, the episode terminates.
为此 首先注意 如果机器人摔倒了 这一阶段结束
And that's a missed opportunity to collect more of this positive reward.
这样就失去了收集这种积极奖励的机会
And in general, if the robot walks for ten time steps,
通常 如果机器人行走了 10 个时间步
that's only 10 opportunities to get reward.
则只有 10 个获得奖励的机会
And if it stays walking for 100,
如果一直行走了 100 步
that's a lot more time to collect more reward.
则有更多的时间收集更多的奖励
So if we get the reward in this way,
如果以这种方式获得奖励
the agent will try to keep from falling for as long as possible.
智能体将尝试尽量长时间不摔倒
Next, since the reward is proportional to the forward velocity,
接下来 因为奖励与前进速度成正比
this will ensure the robot also feels pressured to walk as quickly as possible,
这样就确保机器人感受到压力
in the direction of the walking track,
朝着道路的方向尽量快速行走
but it also makes sense to penalize the agent for applying too much force to the joints.
同时 当智能体向接合点应用太多的力时 有必要做出惩罚
This is because otherwise,
因为否则的话
we could end up with a situation where the humanoid walks to erratically.
机器人可能会行走得非常古怪
By penalizing large forces,
通过惩罚很大的力
we can try to keep the movements more smooth and elegant.
可以尝试让动作更加平缓优雅
Likewise, we want to keep the agent on the track and moving forward.
并且 我们希望智能体沿着道路行走并向前移动
Otherwise, who knows where it could end up walking off to.
否则 谁知道它会走到哪里
Of course, the robot can't focus just on walking fast,
当然 机器人不能只侧重于快速行走
or just on moving forward,
或只向前移动
or only on walking smoothly,
或只平缓地行走
or just on walking for as long as possible.
或只尽量走很长的时间
These are four somewhat competing requirements that the agent has to balance for
智能体在朝着最大化期望累积奖励目标前进的所有时间步中
all time steps towards its goal of maximizing expected cumulative reward.
必须平衡所有这四个相互影响的要求
And Google DeepMind demonstrated that from this very simple reward function,
Google DeepMind 团队的研究结果表明 根据这个非常简单的奖励函数
the agent is able to learn how to walk in a very human like fashion.
智能体能够学会以非常像人类的方式行走
In fact, this rewards function is so simple
实际上 这个奖励函数如此的简单
that it may seem that deciding reward is quite straightforward,
似乎让我们觉得判断奖励很简单
but in general, this is not the case.
但通常并非如此
Of course, there are some counterexamples to this.
当然 有一些反例
For instance, if you're teaching an agent to play a video game,
例如 如果你指导智能体玩视频游戏
the reward is just the score on the screen.
奖励就只是屏幕上的得分
And if you're teaching an agent to play Backgammon, well,
如果指导智能体玩双陆棋
the reward is delivered only at the end of the game,
奖励将仅在游戏结束时体现出来
and you could construct it to be positive if the agent wins,
可以表示为如果智能体赢了 则是正面奖励
and negative, if it loses.
如果输了 则是负面奖励
The fact, that the reward is so simple is
实际上 正是奖励如此简单
precisely what makes this research from DeepMind so fascinating.
使得 DeepMind 的研究很有趣